Ezio Martinelli Papers
Ezio Martinelli Papers
1927-1968
Martinelli, Ezio, 1913-1980.
5.25 linear ft.
Correspondence, family, business, and personal (1927-1967); artwork, including photographs and reproductions of Martinelli's United Nations commission; statements on his work; and printed material, including clippings about Martinelli (1928-1968), and exhibition announcements, catalogs, and invitations (1934-1968). Correspondents include Aldo John Casanova, Ed Colker, Martin Craig, Dorothy Dehner, Helmut von Erffa, Giannetto Fieschi, Horace Gregory, Peter Grippe, Edmund Haines, Stanley Hayter, Louis I. Kahn, Leon Kelly, Leon Kroll, Norman Lewis, Sam Maitin, Barbara Brooks Morgan, Marnie Pomeroy, Melville Price, Walter Reinsel, Theodore Roszak, Charles Seide, Helena Simkhovitch, David Smith, and Carl Zigrosser.
149497
Biographical History
Ezio Martinelli (1913-1980) was an Italian-American sculptor and painter. He was a WPA artist and part of the Abstract Expressionist movement, along with others such as Willem de Kooning, Grace Hartigan, and Jackson Pollock. He studied at the Academy of Fine Arts in Bologna and the National Academy of Design in New York, and later taught at Sarah Lawrence College, the American Academy in Rome, and Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture in Maine.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1927 to 1968, the Ezio Martinelli Papers comprises family and general correspondence, artwork, writings, and memorabilia of the New Jersey-born artist. Illuminating Martinelli's artistic style as well as his Italian heritage, the collection documents both the career and personal life of the painter, sculptor, printmaker, etcher, engraver, and educator.
Arranged chronologically, the Family correspondence (Box 1) consists primarily of incoming letters from 1954 to 1963 from Martinelli's parents. The general Correspondence (Boxes 1-3), also in chronological sequence, spans the years 1927 to 1967 and is composed of both incoming and outgoing letters. In the interest of preservation, photocopies were made of the deteriorating outgoing carbons and are interfiled in the Correspondence. Correspondents include artists (Aldo John Casanova, Edward I. Colker, Martin Craig, Dorothy Dehner, Giannetto Fieschi, Peter Grippe, Stanley William and Helen Phillips Hayter, Leon Kelly, Leon Kroll, Norman Lewis, Richard Lippold, Samuel Maitin, Frank R. Metz, Barbara Brooks Morgan, Oke Gustaf Nordgren, Melville Price, Walter Reinsel, Kurt Roesch, Theodore J. Roszak, Charles Seide, Charles Seliger, Helena Simkhovitch, David Smith, Helmut Von Erffa, Carl Zigrosser); and art-related institutions (American Federation of Arts, Art Institute of Chicago, Brooklyn Museum, Carnegie Institute, Cleveland Institute of Art, Elgin Academy, Ford Foundation, Gotham Gallery, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, International Graphic Arts Society, Inc., Morris Gallery, National Association of Women Artists, Inc., National Institute of Arts and Letters, Newark Museum, Philadelphia Museum College of Art, Philadelphia Museum of Art, Print Club of Philadelphia, Print Council of America, Ringling Museum of Art, United States. Information Agency, United States. Public Buildings Administration, Whitney Museum of American Art, Willard Gallery). Among additional correspondents are literary figures (Giovanni Carandente, Paul Cummings, Horace Gregory, Marnie Pomeroy); museum curators (Richard Eugene Fuller, Lloyd Goodrich, Una E. Johnson, Katharine Kuh, Carl O. Schniewind, James Johnson Sweeney, Mahonri Sharp Young); musician Edmund Haines; patrons and clients (Anne Jefferson, Joint Industry Board of the Electrical Industry, Barbara M. Kaerwer, Charles Kligerman, Albert R. Lee Co., New Directions, Samuel A. Seaver, Elaine and Herb Stanton, S. Sterling Co., Steuben Glass, David P. Wollowick); and university administrators (Pierre Bedard, Emanuel M. Benson, Andrew C. Ritchie, Harold Taylor). A selected index to the Correspondence follows the box list.
Artwork (Boxes 3-4) encompasses catalog design and layout for Sarah Lawrence College, photographs, three printing blocks, and reproductions. Photographs document techniques used to construct the sculpture mounted on the outer wall of the United Nations General Assembly building, and also represent miscellaneous mural designs and sculpture. Reproductions depict the United Nations sculpture in addition to miscellaneous images arranged chronologically (1930-1967). Several statements on art constitute Writings (Box 4).
Memorabilia (Boxes 4-11) includes awards, identification and membership cards, and invitations, financial/legal material, juvenilia, printed material, and typescript reviews by others, as well as information about art associations, fellowships, teaching, and travel. Fellowship material (1956-1966) relative to the John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation consists of applications, correspondence, and published reports. Financial/Legal material (1939-1964) includes contracts, receipts, and sales records pertaining to Martinelli's artwork. Printed material contains newspaper clippings (1928-1968), exhibition material (1934-1968), and published reviews and articles about Martinelli (1936-1967). Catalogs and invitations for Martinelli's group and one-man shows, several posters, and catalogs and information regarding miscellaneous art juries are among the exhibition material. Teaching-related material is arranged by organization title and comprises alumnae magazines, announcements, brochures, catalogs, and newsletters. Travel-related material is specific to Martinelli's month as artist-in-residence at the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art in Sarasota, Florida during the spring of 1964.
Arrangement of the Collection
Corrsepondence is arranged chronologically (see index at the end of this finding aid for notable correspondents). Other series are arranged alphabetically by type or topic.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Sculptors; Art -- Painters; Casanova, Aldo John, 1929-; Colker, Ed, 1927-; Craig, Martin.; Dehner, Dorothy, 1901-1994.; Erffa, Helmut von, 1900-1979.; Fieschi, Giannetto, 1921-; Gregory, Horace, 1898-1982.; Grippe, Peter.; Haines, Edmund.; Hayter, Stanley William, 1901-1988.; Kahn, Louis I., 1901-1974.; Kelly, Leon, 1901-1982.; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974.; Lewis, Norman.; Maitin, Sam.; Martinelli, Ezio, 1913-1980.; Morgan, Barbara Brooks, 1900-1992.; Pomeroy, Marnie.; Price, Melville, 1920-1970.; Reinsel, Walter.; Roszak, Theodore, 1907-1981.; Seide, Charles.; Simkhovitch, Helena.; Smith, David, 1906-1965.; Zigrosser, Carl, 1891-1975.; Art, American.; Italian Americans.; Painters -- United States.; Sculptors -- United States.; Sculpture, American.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Invitations.; Juvenilia.; Artists.; Painters.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ezio Martinelli, 1968, 1969.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Biographical Material (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Family correspondence, 1954-1963 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1957; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1963; 8 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1967; 3 folders (Box 3)
- Artwork
  - Catalog design and layout, Sarah Lawrence College, 1959; undated (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    - "Manes Flayed II" (sculpture), 1954-1955 (Oversize 1)
    - United Nations sculpture, undated (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939; undated (Box 3)
  - Printing blocks, 3 blocks in 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Reproductions
    - United Nations sculpture, 1961-1964; undated (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1967; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
- Writings
  - Statements on art, 1955; 1964,; undated (Box 4)
- Memorabilia
  - Art associations
    - American Federation of Arts, 1956-1960 (Box 4)
    - Ford Foundation, 1957; 1961 (Box 4)
    - International Graphic Arts Society, Inc., 1957-1962 (Box 4)
    - Morris Gallery, 1958 (?) (Box 4)
    - Print Council of America, 1958-1963; undated (Box 4)
    - Willard Gallery, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (A-Z), 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Awards, identification and membership cards, andinvitations, 1934-1966 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
      - Application material (Box 4)
      - Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 4)
      - Reports, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Financial and legal
    - Contracts, receipts, sales records, etc., 1939-1964; undated (Box 5)
  - Juvenilia, 1928-1936; undated (Box 5)
  - Printed material
    - Clippings, 1928-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Exhibition material
      - Announcements, itineraries, etc., 1934-1967; undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Catalogs, invitations
        - Group shows, 1934-1955; 8 folders of 23 (Box 6)
        - Group shows, 1955-1962; 7 folders of 23 (Box 7)
        - Group shows, 1962-1968; undated; 8 folders of 23 (Box 8)
        - One man shows, 1946-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Photographs, 1960 (Box 9)
      - Posters, 1957; 1960,; 1968 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous art juries, 1938-1967; undated (Box 9)
    - Reviews, articles about, 1936-1964; 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Reviews, articles about, 1965-1967; undated; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Teaching related
    - Parsons School of Design
      - Alumnae magazine, art class brochure, teachingschedule, 1955-1964 (Box 10)
      - Catalogs, 1954-1964; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Philadelphia Museum School of Industrial Art
      - Workshop brochures and subscription information, 1947-1949 (Box 10)
    - Print club
      - Announcements, undated (Box 10)
    - Sarah Lawrence College
      - Alumnae magazine, catalog, newsletters, report, 1958-1968; undated (Box 11)
      - Course catalogs, 1947-1964; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Travel-related
    - John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art, Florida, 1964 (Box 11)
  - Typescript reviews by others, undated (Box 11)
  - Miscellany (Box 11)
Selected Index to Correspondence
American Federation of Arts 1947 May 14 1947 Dec. 3 1948 June 2 1949 Feb. 28 1949 May 2 1950 Jan. 26 1956 Feb. 24 1957 Feb. 8 1957 May 22 1958 Apr. 9 1959 Jan. 21 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1959 Feb. 9 1963 July 22 (outgoing typescript draft) 1963 Sept. 24 (attached: carbon of letter sent by AFA to John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art) 1963 Sept. 29 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Jan. 29 See also Memorabilia: Art Associations
Andersen, Wayne V. 1957 Aug. 23 1957 Aug. 29 (outgoing typescript photocopy)
Arnheim, Rudolf 1965 Dec. 17 undated
Art in America 1955 Aug. 25 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1955 Oct. 25 (to Willard Gallery) 1955 Nov. 2 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1961 Apr. 25 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 May 3 1963 Nov. 25 1963 Dec. 2 (outgoing typescript carbon with attached biographical material) 1963 Dec. 3 1963 Dec. 8 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Jan. 8 1964 Jan. 9 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Jan. 18 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Feb. 10 1966 Sept. 25 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Art Institute of Chicago 1945 May 31 1945 June 5 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1946 Mar. 3 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1946 Mar. 11 1946 June 8 1946 June 17 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1947 Feb. 6 1947 Mar. 17 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1947 Mar. 27 1951 Dec. 21 1953 Jan. 16 1955 Jan. 27 (telegram) 1955 Feb. 3 1955 Feb. 17 1955 Apr. 4 1956 June 20 1956 June 21 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1961 Oct. 23 1962 Jan. 30 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Feb. 6
Bedard, Pierre 1956 Apr. 28 1956 June 20 1957 May 2 1958 Apr. 20 (outgoing typescript photocopy)
Benson, Emanuel M. and Gertrude Acherman 1952 Dec. 9 1953 Mar. 15 1955 Feb. 17 1958 Apr. 8 1958 June 18 1959 Oct. 20 1959 Oct. 30 1959 Oct. 31 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1961 Mar. 29 1961 Oct. 23 (assistant to Benson, Herbert H. Hickmott)
Bok, Curtis 1940 Mar. 21 (to Martinelli's wife)
Brennan, Sherry (first wife?) 1938 July 8 (poetry) 1940 Aug. 29 (from the Barnes Foundation) 1941 Jan. 4 (note on reverse of Albany Institute of History and Art letter) undated
Brooklyn Museum 1951 Nov. 5 1952 Jan. 28 1952 May 20 1956 June 20 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 May 5 1959 Mar. 3
Carandente, Giovanni 1965 Dec. 21 (change of address notification) 1966 Jan. 10 (in Italian) 1966 Feb. 11 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Carnegie Institute 1950 Aug. 7 1950 Aug. 22 1950 Nov. 8 1957 Dec. 31 1958 Jan. 8 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Jan. 15 1958 Apr. 20 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Apr. 22 1959 Feb. 11 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1959 June 19 1959 June 22 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1960 May 6 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Casanova, Aldo John 1965 Nov. 29 1965 Dec. 3 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1965 Dec. 10 1966 June 25
Cleveland Institute of Art 1966 Feb. 25
Colker, Edward I. 1956 Jan. 11 1957 June 30 1959 Nov. 2 1960 Oct. 18 (attached: Colker's partial Guggenheim application) 1961 May 4 1962 Feb. 21 1962 May 20 1962 Sept. 9 1963 Apr. 15
Craig, Martin 1957 June 29 1958 May 15
Cummings, Paul 1963 May 8
Dehner, Dorothy 1959 Feb. 26 1959 Mar. 7 (outgoing typescript carbon on reverse of Feb. 26 letter) 1959 Mar. 9 1959 July 29 (postcard) 1961 Oct. 30 (index card)
Elgin Academy (Elgin, Illinois) 1941 May 2 (telegram) 1941 May 6
Fieschi, Giannetto 1959 Apr. 28 1959 Sept. 9
Ford Foundation 1958 July 23 1958 Sept. 20 (outgoing typescript photocopy with nominee list) 1959 Feb. 4 1959 May 22 1960 Jan. 18 1962 Dec. 28 1963 Jan. 1 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 Jan. 14 1963 Jan. 14 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 Jan. 23 (photocopy to the Museum of Modern Art) 1963 Mar. 15 1963 Mar. 21 (outgoing typescript carbon) See also Memorabilia: Art Associations
Fujita, S. Neil undated
Fuller, Richard Eugene 1956 June 22 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy)
Giordano, Frank A. and Lillian 1957 Jan. 22 1957 June 12 1957 Sept. 13 1957 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 May 21 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 May 26 1958 May 29 1958 Sept. 5 1959 Oct. 4 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1959 Nov. 19 1961 Oct. 21 (carbon of letter sent to the United Nations) 1961 Oct. 24 1962 May 8 1966 Mar. 9
Goodrich, Lloyd 1956 June 26 1958 Apr. 23(outgoing typescript photocopy)
Gotham Gallery (New Hope, Pennsylvania) 1961 June 21 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 Sept. 13 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Jan. 16 1962 Feb. 16 (outgoing typescript carbon) undated (3 items)
Gregory, Horace 1951 May 28 (postcard) 1951 (postcard) 1952 Aug. 3 1952 Aug. 15
Grippe, Peter 1952 Aug. 6 1964 Apr. 8
[John Simon] Guggenheim Memorial Foundation See Memorabilia: Fellowships
[Solomon R.] Guggenheim Museum 1952 Dec. 18 1957 July 17 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1957 July 22 1957 Sept. 14 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1957 Sept. 16 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 May 15 1963 Mar. 28 1963 Apr. 22 1963 Apr. 25 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 May 10 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1966 Apr. 28 1966 May 11 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1966 May 23 1966 June 7 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1966 Sept. 25 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Haines, Edmund 1957 Mar. 22 1957 May 1 1966 Feb. 1
Hayter, Stanley William and Helen Phillips 1953 Jan. 23 (original card by H. P.) 1955 Jan. 8 (original card by S. W.) 1955 Feb. 2 (exhibition catalog of S. W.) 1960 May 11 (postcard) 1960 May 19 (outgoing typescript carbon) undated (4 letters)
International Graphic Arts Society, Inc. 1956 Jan. 3 1956 Nov. 9 1957 Jan. 14 1957 Jan. 18 1957 Mar. 8 1961 May 5 1961 June 14 1961 June 15 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 Dec. 15 1963 July 5 1963 Dec. 30 See also Memorabilia: Art Associations
Jefferson, Anne 1957 Nov. 19 1958 Oct. 10
Johnson, Una E. See Brooklyn Museum
Joint Industry Board of the Electrical Industry (New York City) 1964 May 25 1964 June 21 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Kaerwer, Barbara M. 1959 Jan. 23 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1959 Jan. 30 1959 Jan. or Feb. (?) (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1959 Apr. 21 1959 May 4 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Kahn, Louis I. 1958 Apr. 8
Kelly, Leon 1946 Sept. 12 1946 Sept. 25
Kligerman, Charles 1958 Nov. 18 1959 Jan. 23 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Kligerman, Joshua C. 1961 Apr. 5 1961 Aug. 30 1961 Sept. 21 1961 Sept. 30 (outgoing typescript carbon with price list of artwork) 1961 Oct. 2 1961 Nov. 20 1961 Nov. 28 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 Dec. 27 (outgoing typescript carbon with price list of artwork) 1961 Dec. (?) 1962 Dec. (?) 1963 Jan. 1 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 Feb. 9 1963 May 3 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 May 15 1963 May 18 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 Sept. 29 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 Oct. 14 1964 Feb. 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Mar. 5 1964 May 2 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 May 26 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 May (?) 1964 May or June (?) 1964 June 3 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Kroll, Leon 1957 July 17 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1957 July 24 1957 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Apr. 20 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Oct. 10 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Oct. 13 1959 Apr. 13 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 Jan. 20 (stamped signature)
Kuh, Katharine 1947 Feb. 6 1947 Mar. 27 1956 July 9 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy)
Laughlin, James See New Directions
Albert R. Lee Co. 1959 Apr. 20 (outgoing typescript original and carbon)
Lewis, Norman 1957 Mar. 25 (?) 1957 Apr. 27 1957 May 31
Lippold, Richard 1959 Dec. 4
Lord & Taylor 1948 Sept. 28 1948 Nov. 8 1948 Nov. 9 (typescript copy to Mrs. Gardner, Sarah Lawrence College) 1950 May 4 1950 May 12 1950 May 19 1952 May 1
Maitin, Samuel 1966 Oct. 11 1966 Oct. 17 (outgoing typescript carbon) undated
Metz, Frank R. 1957 June 25
Moholy-Nagy, Sibyl 1959 Nov. 13 1959 Nov. 22 (outgoing typescript photocopy)
Morgan, Barbara Brooks 1957 May 30 1957 Nov. 12 (postcard) 1961 Sept. (?) (postcard) 1961 Oct. 21 1961 Nov. 24 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Jan. 7
Morris Gallery (New York City) 1955 Feb. 15 1956 July 18 1956 Dec. 18 1958 Mar. 25 (postcard) 1960 Sept. 3 See also Memorabilia: Art Associations
National Association of Women Artists, Inc. 1959 Feb. 26 1959 Apr. 19
National Institute of Arts and Letters 1957 Oct. 10 1957 Nov. 22 1958 Nov. 24 1958 Dec. 1 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Dec. 3 1958 Dec. (?) (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1959 Apr. 2 1959 Apr. 3 1961 Jan. 12 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 Jan. 20 1966 Mar. 10 1966 Mar. 17 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1966 Mar. 17 1966 Mar. 18 1966 Apr. 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1966 May 11 1966 June 7 undated (outgoing typescript photocopy) See also Memorabilia: Awards, Identification and Membership Cards, Invitations
New Directions 1963 May 16 1963 May 18 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 May 31
Newark Museum 1947 June 27 1947 Aug. 4 1964 Apr. 22 1964 May 11 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Nordgren, Oke Gustaf 1947 June 7
Philadelphia Museum College of Art 1946 Mar. 4 1949 Sept. 23 1955 Feb. 17 (?) 1958 Apr. 8 1958 June 18 1959 Oct. 20 1959 Oct. 30 1959 Oct. 31 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1961 Mar. 29 1961 Oct. 23
Philadelphia Museum of Art 1943 Dec. 30 1952 Dec. 9 1956 Mar. 15 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1956 Mar. 21 1956 Mar. 29 1961 Sept. 25 1962 Apr. 13 1962 Apr. 18 1967 Mar. 22
Philadelphia Museum School of Art See Philadelphia Museum College of Art
Philadelphia Museum School of Industrial Art See Philadelphia Museum College of Art Memorabilia: Teaching-related
Pomeroy, Marnie 1954 June 1954 Aug. 10 (?) 1954 Nov. 30 (?) 1955 Feb. 8 (?) 1955 June 29 1955 Nov. 10 1956 June (?) 1956 Oct. (?) 1957 Dec. 11 1958 Sept. 25 undated
Prentice Hall Publishers 1962 Feb. 15 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Apr. 4 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Apr. 11
Price, Melville and Barbara 1962 Mar. 26 (postcard) 1962 May 29 undated
Print Club (Philadelphia) 1944 Oct. 26 1944 Nov. 15 1944 Dec. 21 1944 Dec. 27 1946 Feb. 9 (typescript carbon from the Shipley School) 1947 Feb. 24 1947 Dec. 4 1948 Jan. 19 1948 Apr. 12 1948 Dec. 8 (postcard) 1948 Dec. 10 (postcard) 1948 Dec. 20 1948 Dec. 29 1949 Jan. 5 1949 Sept. 8 1949 Sept. 15 1950 Sept. 14 1952 Jan. 31 1952 Mar. 27 1952 Apr. 21 1952 Sept. 16 1952 Oct. 16 1953 Dec. 11 1954 Sept. 24 1956 June 22 1962 Oct. 3 1962 Oct. 15 See also Memorabilia: Teaching-related
Print Council of America 1957 May 3 1961 Oct. 31 1961 Nov. 28 1961 Dec. 20 1961 Dec. 26 1962 Jan. 3 (2 form letters) 1962 Jan. 15 (outgoing typescript carbon of list of prints) 1962 Jan. 26 1962 Feb. 5 1962 Feb. 11 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Feb. (?) 1962 Mar. 1962 June 18 1963 Jan. 21 1963 June 12 1963 July 11 See also Memorabilia: Art Associations
Reinsel, Walter 1958 Mar. 1 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Apr. 28 1958 Aug. 5 1958 Aug. 27 1958 Aug. (?) (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1964 May 26 1964 June 3 (outgoing typescript carbon)
[John and Mable] Ringling Museum of Art 1963 Sept. 27 1963 Oct. 15 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Feb. 19 1964 Feb. 26 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Apr. 15 1964 Apr. 17 (2 outgoing typescript carbons) 1964 June 14 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 June (?) See also Memorabilia: Travel-related
Ritchie, Andrew C. 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 May 5
Roesch, Kurt 1947 June 3 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1955 July 19
Roszak, Theodore J. 1954 July 21 1955 Aug. 16 1956 Dec. (?) 1958 Aug. 8 (postcard) 1958 Aug. 27 1960 Oct. 6 (postcard) 1962 (personalized greeting card)
Sarah Lawrence College See Taylor, Harold Artwork: Catalog design and layout Memorabilia: Teaching-related
Scarmolin, A. Louis 1947 May 19
Schniewind, Carl O. 1945 May 31 1945 June 5 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1946 Mar. 3 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1946 Mar. 11 1946 June 8 1946 June 17 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1947 Mar. 17 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1951 Dec. 21 1953 Jan. 16 1956 June 20
Seaver, Samuel A. 1961 Nov. 6 1962 Jan. 19 (note) 1962 Jan. 30 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1964 Feb. 13 1964 Feb. 15 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Seide, Charles 1946 May 18 undated
Seliger, Charles 1958 July 10 (artwork attached) 1958 Sept. 17
Simkhovitch, Helena 1957 July 27 1957 July 29 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1957 Oct. 23 (postcard) 1958 Mar. 8 (postcard) 1958 June 20
Smith, David 1950 Sept. 6 1950 Sept. 30 undated
Stanton, Elaine and Herb 1961 June 30 1961 July 10 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 July (?) 1961 Aug. 3 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 Aug. (?) 1961 Sept. 13 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 July 1 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 July 24 1966 Mar. 9 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1966 Mar. 31 1966 Apr. 7 (outgoing typescript carbon)
S. Sterling Company 1961 Nov. 28 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1961 Dec. 12 1961 Dec. 26 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Steuben Glass 1957 Dec. 16 1958 Jan. 21 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 Jan. 27 1958 July 17 1958 Sept. 25 1959 Mar. 27 1959 June 12 1960 Sept. 27 (attached: press release describing engraved crystal)
Swarthmore College 1945 Mar. 25 1945 May 19 1946 Mar. 3 1946 Apr. 14
Sweeney, James Johnson 1952 Dec. 18 1957 July 17 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1957 July 22 1957 Sept. 14 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1957 Sept. 16 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy) 1958 May 15
Taylor, Harold 1948 Dec. 1 1950 Nov. 21 1958 Apr. 23 (outgoing typescript photocopy)
Toch, Maximilian 1935 Apr. 29
United States. Federal Works Agency. Public Buildings Administration See United States. Public Buildings Administration
United States. Public Buildings Administration 1940 Nov. 2 1941 Jan. 9 1941 Jan. 14 1941 Dec. 18 (Art Week National Exhibition Headquarters)